{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes M, H, V, F and directed edges M->F, V->F, H->V, M->V, H->F.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome F.", "answer": "[{'M', 'H'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome F.", "answer": "{'M', 'H'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome F.", "answer": "{'M', 'H'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is set() a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome F?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome F?\nA. {'M'}\nB. set()\nC. {'H'}\nD. {'M', 'H'}", "answer": "D"}], "uid": "74089888", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes X, V, Z, M and directed edges X->Z, V->Z, X->M, V->M, X->V.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome Z.", "answer": "[{'X'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome Z.", "answer": "{'X'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome Z.", "answer": "{'X'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'X'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome M?", "answer": "Yes."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome M?\nA. {'Z'}\nB. {'Z', 'X'}\nC. {'X'}\nD. set()", "answer": "C"}], "uid": "06569748", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes L, C, B, R, E and directed edges L->C, B->R, L->R, L->B, C->E, R->E.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment B and outcome R.", "answer": "[{'L'}, {'C', 'L'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment B and outcome R.", "answer": "{'L'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment B and outcome R.", "answer": "{'C', 'L'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'E'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment B and outcome R?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment B and outcome R?\nA. {'E', 'C'}\nB. {'E', 'L'}\nC. {'L'}\nD. set()", "answer": "C"}], "uid": "03794006", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes T, A, Q, I, L and directed edges T->A, Q->L, Q->I, A->Q, I->L.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment A and outcome Q.", "answer": "[set(), {'T'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment A and outcome Q.", "answer": "set()"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment A and outcome Q.", "answer": "{'T'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'T', 'L', 'A'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment Q and outcome I?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment Q and outcome I?\nA. {'L'}\nB. {'T', 'L'}\nC. set()\nD. {'T', 'L', 'A'}", "answer": "C"}], "uid": "71494588", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes P, X, K, W, L, N and directed edges P->L, K->L, P->N, K->N, W->N, L->N, P->X.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment L and outcome N.", "answer": "[{'P', 'K'}, {'P', 'W', 'K'}, {'P', 'K', 'X'}, {'P', 'W', 'K', 'X'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment L and outcome N.", "answer": "{'P', 'K'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment L and outcome N.", "answer": "{'P', 'W', 'K', 'X'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'P', 'W', 'K'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment L and outcome N?", "answer": "Yes."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment L and outcome N?\nA. {'P', 'K'}\nB. {'P', 'W'}\nC. {'W', 'X'}\nD. {'K'}", "answer": "A"}], "uid": "78082402", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes Y, U, X, S, W, G and directed edges U->W, U->G, S->G, S->W, Y->W, Y->X, U->X, X->S, X->G, U->S, Y->U.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment X and outcome W.", "answer": "[{'Y', 'U'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment X and outcome W.", "answer": "{'Y', 'U'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment X and outcome W.", "answer": "{'Y', 'U'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'W', 'G', 'U'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment X and outcome S?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment X and outcome W?\nA. {'Y', 'U'}\nB. {'S', 'U'}\nC. set()\nD. {'G'}", "answer": "A"}], "uid": "78917882", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes B, O, J, I, M, H, X and directed edges B->X, J->I, O->J, M->H, M->X, J->X, J->H, O->H, O->X, H->X, B->J, I->M.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment I and outcome H.", "answer": "[{'J'}, {'J', 'B'}, {'J', 'O'}, {'J', 'B', 'O'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment I and outcome H.", "answer": "{'J'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment I and outcome H.", "answer": "{'J', 'B', 'O'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'B', 'O', 'H'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome X?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment I and outcome M?\nA. {'O'}\nB. {'B', 'O', 'X'}\nC. {'J', 'O', 'X'}\nD. {'J', 'O', 'H'}", "answer": "A"}], "uid": "29807252", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes Z, H, Q, K, W, L, X and directed edges W->L, H->Q, L->X, Q->X, Q->L, H->K, Q->K, Z->Q, Z->H, Z->W, Q->W, K->W.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment Q and outcome X.", "answer": "[{'Z', 'H'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment Q and outcome X.", "answer": "{'Z', 'H'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment Q and outcome X.", "answer": "{'Z', 'H'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'Z'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment H and outcome X?", "answer": "Yes."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment W and outcome L?\nA. {'Z', 'X'}\nB. {'K', 'Q', 'Z', 'H', 'X'}\nC. {'X'}\nD. {'Z', 'H', 'Q'}", "answer": "D"}], "uid": "30111585", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes N, U, P, O, L, X, C, D and directed edges U->D, L->C, X->C, N->X, P->C, L->X, O->L, N->D, N->L, C->D, O->D.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment L and outcome D.", "answer": "[{'O', 'N'}, {'P', 'O', 'N'}, {'O', 'N', 'U'}, {'P', 'O', 'N', 'U'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment L and outcome D.", "answer": "{'O', 'N'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment L and outcome D.", "answer": "{'P', 'O', 'N', 'U'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'P', 'N', 'O', 'U', 'L'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment X and outcome C?", "answer": "Yes."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment C and outcome D?\nA. {'P', 'L', 'O'}\nB. {'P', 'X', 'N', 'U'}\nC. {'P', 'L', 'U'}\nD. {'P', 'L', 'X'}", "answer": "D"}], "uid": "78064016", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes A, H, V, O, T, W, F, N and directed edges H->F, W->F, A->V, H->N, T->N, H->T, T->F, A->O, A->T.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment T and outcome N.", "answer": "[{'H'}, {'V', 'H'}, {'H', 'O'}, {'H', 'A'}, {'W', 'H'}, {'V', 'H', 'O'}, {'A', 'V', 'H'}, {'W', 'V', 'H'}, {'H', 'A', 'O'}, {'W', 'H', 'O'}, {'W', 'H', 'A'}, {'A', 'V', 'H', 'O'}, {'W', 'V', 'H', 'O'}, {'A', 'W', 'V', 'H'}, {'W', 'H', 'A', 'O'}, {'V', 'H', 'O', 'A', 'W'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment T and outcome N.", "answer": "{'H'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment T and outcome N.", "answer": "{'V', 'H', 'O', 'A', 'W'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'O', 'A'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment T and outcome F?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment T and outcome N?\nA. {'F', 'H', 'A'}\nB. {'W', 'H', 'A'}\nC. {'F'}\nD. {'W', 'V'}", "answer": "B"}], "uid": "05280395", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes N, I, B, M, O, K, W, A, C and directed edges I->M, M->O, N->A, M->K, O->W, N->O, K->C, N->B, O->A, M->A, B->M, I->K.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment B and outcome K.", "answer": "[set(), {'I'}, {'N'}, {'I', 'N'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment B and outcome K.", "answer": "set()"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment B and outcome K.", "answer": "{'I', 'N'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'B', 'W'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment M and outcome K?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment B and outcome A?\nA. {'C', 'K', 'N', 'M', 'O'}\nB. {'C', 'I', 'K', 'N', 'W'}\nC. {'M', 'I', 'K', 'N'}\nD. {'I', 'N'}", "answer": "D"}], "uid": "18307059", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes Y, O, X, Z, V, W, R, N, B and directed edges O->W, X->V, O->R, Z->N, Z->V, O->N, Y->B, V->W, W->B.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome W.", "answer": "[set(), {'Y'}, {'R'}, {'Z'}, {'O'}, {'X'}, {'R', 'Y'}, {'Z', 'Y'}, {'O', 'Y'}, {'X', 'Y'}, {'R', 'Z'}, {'R', 'O'}, {'R', 'X'}, {'Z', 'N'}, {'Z', 'O'}, {'Z', 'X'}, {'O', 'N'}, {'O', 'X'}, {'R', 'Z', 'Y'}, {'R', 'O', 'Y'}, {'R', 'X', 'Y'}, {'Z', 'N', 'Y'}, {'Z', 'O', 'Y'}, {'Z', 'X', 'Y'}, {'O', 'N', 'Y'}, {'O', 'X', 'Y'}, {'R', 'Z', 'N'}, {'R', 'Z', 'O'}, {'R', 'Z', 'X'}, {'R', 'O', 'N'}, {'R', 'O', 'X'}, {'Z', 'O', 'N'}, {'X', 'Z', 'N'}, {'Z', 'O', 'X'}, {'X', 'O', 'N'}, {'R', 'Z', 'N', 'Y'}, {'R', 'Z', 'O', 'Y'}, {'R', 'Z', 'X', 'Y'}, {'R', 'O', 'N', 'Y'}, {'R', 'O', 'X', 'Y'}, {'Z', 'O', 'N', 'Y'}, {'X', 'Z', 'N', 'Y'}, {'Z', 'O', 'X', 'Y'}, {'X', 'O', 'N', 'Y'}, {'R', 'Z', 'O', 'N'}, {'R', 'Z', 'X', 'N'}, {'R', 'Z', 'O', 'X'}, {'R', 'O', 'N', 'X'}, {'X', 'Z', 'O', 'N'}, {'Y', 'R', 'Z', 'N', 'O'}, {'Y', 'R', 'Z', 'N', 'X'}, {'Y', 'R', 'Z', 'O', 'X'}, {'Y', 'R', 'N', 'O', 'X'}, {'Y', 'Z', 'N', 'O', 'X'}, {'R', 'Z', 'N', 'O', 'X'}, {'Y', 'R', 'Z', 'N', 'O', 'X'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome W.", "answer": "set()"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome W.", "answer": "{'Y', 'R', 'Z', 'N', 'O', 'X'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'W', 'X', 'Y'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome B?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome W?\nA. {'Z'}\nB. {'R', 'B', 'X', 'Y'}\nC. {'B', 'Y', 'R', 'Z', 'N'}\nD. {'R', 'B'}", "answer": "A"}], "uid": "31163291", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes G, J, B, C, directed edges G->B, G->J, J->C, G->C, B->C, J->B and bi-directed edges B<->C, G<->B.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome B.", "answer": "[{'G'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome B.", "answer": "{'G'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome B.", "answer": "{'G'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'C', 'G'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome B?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome B?\nA. {'C', 'G'}\nB. set()\nC. {'C'}\nD. {'G'}", "answer": "D"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment B and outcome C?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "06995451", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes F, T, J, O, directed edges T->J, T->O, J->O, F->O, F->T, F->J and bi-directed edges F<->T, F<->J.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome O.", "answer": "[{'F', 'T'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome O.", "answer": "{'F', 'T'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome O.", "answer": "{'F', 'T'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'F'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome O?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome O?\nA. {'F', 'T'}\nB. set()\nC. {'F'}\nD. {'T'}", "answer": "A"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome O?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "67147051", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes Y, V, G, N, L, directed edges G->L, V->N, Y->G, V->L and bi-directed edges Y<->L.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment G and outcome L.", "answer": "[{'Y'}, {'V', 'Y'}, {'N', 'Y'}, {'V', 'N', 'Y'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment G and outcome L.", "answer": "{'Y'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment G and outcome L.", "answer": "{'V', 'N', 'Y'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'V'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment G and outcome L?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment G and outcome L?\nA. {'V', 'N'}\nB. {'V', 'Y'}\nC. {'V'}\nD. set()", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment G and outcome L?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "08245012", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes A, N, J, V, F, directed edges A->V, A->F, N->V, N->J, A->J, J->V, N->F, V->F, A->N, J->F and bi-directed edges A<->N, N<->F.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome F.", "answer": "[{'J', 'N', 'A'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome F.", "answer": "{'J', 'N', 'A'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment V and outcome F.", "answer": "{'J', 'N', 'A'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'F', 'V', 'A'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment N and outcome J?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment N and outcome V?\nA. {'A'}\nB. {'J'}\nC. set()\nD. {'J', 'A'}", "answer": "A"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment N and outcome F?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "70568578", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes L, R, S, E, J, G, directed edges R->G, J->G, E->J, R->E, L->S, L->J, L->G, E->G, L->R, S->G, R->S, S->E and bi-directed edges R<->J.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment S and outcome G.", "answer": "[{'R', 'L'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment S and outcome G.", "answer": "{'R', 'L'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment S and outcome G.", "answer": "{'R', 'L'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'R'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment S and outcome E?", "answer": "Yes."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment E and outcome J?\nA. {'S'}\nB. {'R', 'S'}\nC. {'L'}\nD. {'L', 'S', 'G'}", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment R and outcome S?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "47944566", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes K, Y, M, C, T, X, directed edges K->M, C->X, K->T, K->Y, C->T, M->T and bi-directed edges C<->X, M<->X, Y<->T, K<->T.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment M and outcome T.", "answer": "[{'K'}, {'C', 'K'}, {'K', 'Y'}, {'C', 'K', 'X'}, {'C', 'K', 'Y'}, {'C', 'K', 'X', 'Y'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment M and outcome T.", "answer": "{'K'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment M and outcome T.", "answer": "{'C', 'K', 'X', 'Y'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'C', 'X', 'Y'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment M and outcome T?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment M and outcome T?\nA. set()\nB. {'Y'}\nC. {'C', 'K', 'Y'}\nD. {'C', 'X'}", "answer": "C"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment M and outcome T?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "63236981", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes Q, P, X, E, Z, B, Y, directed edges Z->Y, X->B, X->E, Q->X, Q->B, X->Y, Q->E, P->Z, E->Z, P->E, E->B, P->X and bi-directed edges P<->Z, B<->Y, X<->Z, Q<->E, X<->E.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment E and outcome B.", "answer": "[{'X', 'Q'}, {'P', 'X', 'Q'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment E and outcome B.", "answer": "{'X', 'Q'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment E and outcome B.", "answer": "{'P', 'X', 'Q'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'P', 'E', 'X'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment Z and outcome Y?", "answer": "Yes."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment Z and outcome Y?\nA. {'P', 'E', 'B', 'Q'}\nB. {'P', 'E', 'Q'}\nC. {'E', 'B', 'X', 'Q'}\nD. {'P', 'B'}", "answer": "C"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment E and outcome B?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "53022153", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes F, J, A, Z, Q, M, V, directed edges J->Q, F->J, Q->V, F->Z, Q->M, J->A and bi-directed edges Q<->V.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome A.", "answer": "[set(), {'F'}, {'Z'}, {'F', 'Z'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome A.", "answer": "set()"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome A.", "answer": "{'F', 'Z'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'Z', 'V', 'Q'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome M?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment J and outcome A?\nA. {'Z', 'V', 'Q'}\nB. {'F'}\nC. {'M', 'V'}\nD. {'F', 'Z', 'M', 'Q'}", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment Q and outcome V?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "21476212", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes J, Z, V, F, N, T, H, B, directed edges N->T, J->V, J->N, T->H, Z->F, F->N, F->T, Z->N, N->H, J->Z, N->B and bi-directed edges Z<->V, V<->H, T<->B, Z<->H, Z<->F, Z<->N, Z<->B.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment T and outcome H.", "answer": "[{'F', 'N'}, {'F', 'V', 'N'}, {'F', 'J', 'N'}, {'F', 'Z', 'N'}, {'F', 'J', 'V', 'N'}, {'F', 'Z', 'V', 'N'}, {'F', 'Z', 'J', 'N'}, {'F', 'V', 'J', 'Z', 'N'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment T and outcome H.", "answer": "{'F', 'N'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment T and outcome H.", "answer": "{'F', 'V', 'J', 'Z', 'N'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'F', 'J', 'N'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment T and outcome H?", "answer": "Yes."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment T and outcome H?\nA. {'F', 'Z', 'B', 'J'}\nB. {'Z', 'V'}\nC. {'F', 'Z', 'V', 'N'}\nD. {'F', 'Z', 'B', 'V'}", "answer": "C"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment F and outcome B?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "42317369", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes X, C, L, S, W, J, I, F, directed edges L->J, S->W, I->F, L->I, C->J, L->W, L->S, C->F, X->F, X->L and bi-directed edges X<->L, X<->I, W<->F, L<->I, C<->I.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment S and outcome W.", "answer": "[{'L'}, {'F', 'L'}, {'C', 'L'}, {'I', 'L'}, {'J', 'L'}, {'L', 'X'}, {'F', 'C', 'L'}, {'F', 'I', 'L'}, {'F', 'J', 'L'}, {'F', 'L', 'X'}, {'C', 'I', 'L'}, {'J', 'C', 'L'}, {'C', 'L', 'X'}, {'J', 'I', 'L'}, {'I', 'L', 'X'}, {'J', 'L', 'X'}, {'F', 'C', 'I', 'L'}, {'F', 'C', 'J', 'L'}, {'F', 'C', 'L', 'X'}, {'F', 'J', 'I', 'L'}, {'F', 'I', 'L', 'X'}, {'F', 'J', 'L', 'X'}, {'J', 'C', 'I', 'L'}, {'C', 'I', 'L', 'X'}, {'J', 'C', 'L', 'X'}, {'J', 'I', 'L', 'X'}, {'F', 'C', 'I', 'J', 'L'}, {'F', 'C', 'I', 'L', 'X'}, {'F', 'C', 'J', 'L', 'X'}, {'F', 'I', 'J', 'L', 'X'}, {'C', 'I', 'J', 'L', 'X'}, {'F', 'C', 'I', 'J', 'L', 'X'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment S and outcome W.", "answer": "{'L'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment S and outcome W.", "answer": "{'F', 'C', 'I', 'J', 'L', 'X'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is set() a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment L and outcome W?", "answer": "Yes."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment I and outcome F?\nA. {'J', 'W', 'L', 'S'}\nB. {'J', 'C', 'W', 'S'}\nC. {'C', 'S'}\nD. {'C', 'S', 'J', 'L', 'W', 'X'}", "answer": "D"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment L and outcome S?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "68063599", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes E, Q, H, I, O, N, B, J, R, directed edges E->N, O->N, I->R, I->N, E->O, B->J, N->R, H->B, Q->B, E->B, O->J and bi-directed edges Q<->B, N<->B, B<->R, J<->R, I<->N, N<->R.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment O and outcome R.", "answer": "[{'E'}, {'E', 'B'}, {'E', 'I'}, {'E', 'Q'}, {'E', 'H'}, {'E', 'B', 'I'}, {'E', 'B', 'Q'}, {'E', 'B', 'H'}, {'E', 'I', 'Q'}, {'E', 'I', 'H'}, {'E', 'H', 'Q'}, {'E', 'B', 'I', 'Q'}, {'E', 'B', 'I', 'H'}, {'E', 'B', 'H', 'Q'}, {'E', 'I', 'H', 'Q'}, {'B', 'I', 'Q', 'E', 'H'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment O and outcome R.", "answer": "{'E'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment O and outcome R.", "answer": "{'B', 'I', 'Q', 'E', 'H'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'E', 'B', 'I', 'H'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment O and outcome J?", "answer": "Yes."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment O and outcome N?\nA. {'I', 'Q'}\nB. {'H'}\nC. {'J', 'H'}\nD. {'E', 'B', 'H', 'Q'}", "answer": "D"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment O and outcome R?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "58825043", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes J, K, D, L, N, G, A, M, Q, directed edges N->A, D->G, K->L, N->M, M->Q, L->A, J->L, A->M, N->Q, L->G, D->N, J->G and bi-directed edges J<->Q, J<->G, J<->N, K<->L, L<->A, K<->G, N<->Q, L<->M.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment M and outcome Q.", "answer": "[{'J', 'N'}, {'J', 'K', 'N'}, {'J', 'N', 'D'}, {'J', 'N', 'A'}, {'J', 'L', 'N'}, {'J', 'K', 'N', 'D'}, {'J', 'K', 'N', 'A'}, {'J', 'L', 'K', 'N'}, {'J', 'A', 'N', 'D'}, {'J', 'L', 'N', 'D'}, {'J', 'L', 'N', 'A'}, {'K', 'J', 'N', 'D', 'A'}, {'K', 'J', 'N', 'D', 'L'}, {'K', 'J', 'N', 'A', 'L'}, {'J', 'N', 'D', 'A', 'L'}, {'K', 'J', 'N', 'D', 'A', 'L'}]"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one minimal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment M and outcome Q.", "answer": "{'J', 'N'}"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find one maximal valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment M and outcome Q.", "answer": "{'K', 'J', 'N', 'D', 'A', 'L'}"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is {'G', 'Q'} a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment N and outcome M?", "answer": "No."}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following sets is a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment N and outcome A?\nA. {'J', 'D'}\nB. {'K', 'J', 'M', 'G', 'L'}\nC. {'Q', 'J', 'M', 'G', 'L'}\nD. {'J', 'L', 'D', 'Q'}", "answer": "A"}, {"question_type": "EX", "question": "Does there exist a valid backdoor adjustment set for treatment N and outcome A?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "17486923", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
